The containment operator checks whether a value
is contained within a list of values. Containment
is used most for lists, sets, tuples, and
dictionaries. We will see this operator in
more context later, but let’s run through a quick
code example of the containment. On line 1 of
this 136-containment file, I have listed the
four largest islands in Japan. This variable
may be used in a game later to quiz someone
on identifying one or more islands. Line 2
simulates a guess one is making on an island. The
containment portion, line 3, uses the in keyword
to test to see if, in this case, the island
listed is within the large islands variable.
Assuming I have everything spelled correctly,
the result of this code should read True, as
I have Hokkaido listed as an island both for the
simulated guess and in the list of large islands.
I will run this code, and we do get a True
result. In the order of operators, containment
occurs just after arithmetic. Containment is
in front of comparison, logical, and identity
because containment is not as precise as the
other three comparison types. In containment,
we are just looking for a value within a list
of values: a set, a tuple, or a dictionary. It's
review time. We have seen six types of operators.
Your Review 1.3 exercise in the workbook has a
place for you to list the six operator types
in order of preference and then list what
takes precedence over all the operator types. You
also have a place to list the order of operations
within both the logical operators and arithmetic
operators. The next video will have the answers.